the boys
los chicos
[Music]
[Música]
what the [ __ ] what the [ __ ] is this stuff you
qué [__] qué [__] es estas cosas que
do look I'm really going to quit
hace mira yo ya de verdad voy a dejar
this job I'm
este trabajo
literally going to go to this job because I'm not
literal voy a este trabajo porque no se
good at it I eat things that I shouldn't
me da nada bien me como cosas que no me
eat in every live okay and
tengo que comer en cada directo vale y
in the end in the end it's that well I'm going to
al fin al final es que bueno voy a
hold on a little longer until they kick me out
aguantar un poco más hasta que me eche
hold on until they kick me out okay I'm going to
me aguanta hasta que me echen vale voy a
watch this video that I found that
ver este vídeo que me he encontrado que
I smell like it's going to be a gem I'm
me huelo a que va a ser una joyita
flying it's going to be a gem
me vuelo a que va a ser una joyita
the best gives his opinion on 8m reacting to a
el mejor opina del 8m reaccionando a un
video of Roma Gallardo
vídeo de roma' gallardo
I'm sure you're going to be a gem
seguro que seguro que te vas a una joya
many of them no
muchas de ellas no
I like that song which one do I want without
me mola esa canción cuál la quiero sin
branches I already know that Roma has reacted it's because I've
ramas ya sé que roma ha reaccionado es
seen it on Roma's page that
que lo he visto en la página de roma que
Roma has reacted and well I haven't seen
roma ha reaccionado y bueno no he visto
Roma's reaction there was a reactionary
la reacción de roma había reaccionario
coming the best will surely say some
viniendo el mejor seguro dirá cualquier
[ __ ]
gilipollez
top song for the media keys from
top canción para los medios llaves de
Bogota
bogotá
remember to remember that you appreciate the SUVs
recuerda recordar que agradeces las suvs
right today's string I appreciate your in
cierto el string de hoy agradezco su en
celebration of the 8 m as or
celebración del 8 m como
is another crash in today's string
o sea es otro chocas en el string de hoy
I appreciate the SUVs be or appreciate them
agradezco las suvs sean o las agradece
never no then not
nunca no entonces
of any relationship but because it is not
no de ninguna relación pero porque no es
feminist but let's see asking
feminista pero vamos a ver preguntando a
feminists roma gallardo why not
feministas roma gallardo por qué no
do a thematic stream of milk
hacer un stream temático de leche
since these interviews are like an [ __ ] by
ya estas entrevistas son de capullo by
the way I mean the simple fact of
the way me refiero en simple hecho de
anger to a person there is the demonstration
ira a una persona está la manifestación
and ask him 50,000 technical questions so
y hacerle 50.000 preguntas técnicas para
that he does not know how to answer does not give you the reason
que no sepa responder no te da la razón
and there let's see he is
y ahí a ver
stupid you are very stupid
es tonto eres muy tonto
at the moment at the moment he
de momento de momento
starts insulting romà do these
empieza insultando a romà hacer estas
interviews like an [ __ ]
entrevistas de capullo
from
yo desde aquí le digo al mejor el mejor
here I tell the best the best the romà in a debate he puts your ass good he does to you what what we have eaten in the previous extract that I am going to have to censor it okay accept long debate roma even if roma does not ask you here on my channel I am the
roma yo aquí en mi canal yo hago de
moderator okay tell him the best says
moderador vale decírselo el mejor dice
javi oliveira that you do a debate with
javi oliveira que hagas un debate con
roma on javi's channel I only say to
roma en el canal de javi yo sólo digo a
roma and roma comes okay but it will start
roma y roma viene vale pero empezará
insulting because because when
insultando porque porque cuando se ha
Roma has messed with you and now the second thing the second
metido roma contigo y ahora lo segundo
technical questions
preguntas técnicas
technical questions to go to a
preguntas técnicas para ir a una
feminist demonstration where they are supposed to
manifestación feminista donde se supone
know what they are
que tienen que saber por lo que se están
demonstrating for and you go and ask them, let's see,
manifestando y vas y le preguntas a ver
tell me all the points of the
dime todos los puntos del panfleto
feminist pamphlet that you are defending and they don't
feminista que estás defendiendo y no se
know it,
lo sepa
those are technical questions so that they don't
eso son preguntas técnicas para que no
know how to answer, I
sepan responder
mean, if they don't know how to answer, it seems like an [ __ ] to me, it
o sea si no saben responder a mí me
seems like an [ __ ] to me, it
parece de capullo me parece de capullo
seems like an [ __ ] to go to a
me parece de capullo ir a una
demonstration and not know what you are
manifestación y no saber ni lo que estás
defending or what you are
defendiendo ni saber lo que estás
claiming,
reivindicando
that's what seems like an [ __ ] to me,
eso es lo que me parece a mí de capullo
but where,
pero por donde por de bala para por
where the video goes, well the reality is
dónde va el vídeo bueno la realidad es
that although I go a little way for there to
que aunque edano un poco de camino para
be equality in every
que haya una igualdad en todos los
sense between men and women, for
sentidos entre el hombre y la mujer para
good, dad wants to dip the churro, the
bien papá quiere mojar el churro el
fleece
vellón
I want to dip the churro
quiero mojar el churro
there, the best it seems to me, I'm going to watch the
ahí el mejor me parece voy a ver el
video, the best feminist, the best
vídeo el mejor feminista el mejor
feminist but then he tells his ex-girlfriend
feminista pero luego a su ex novia le
that if it weren't for him, she would be
dice que si no fuera por él estaría
working in more where the usual ones,
trabajando en más donde las habituales
the salsa singer was now working
el salsero ahora estaba trabajando
calmly and that I get a
tranquilamente y que me llega
notification because let's see the salsa singer is going to be
notificación pues a ver el salsero va a
seeing the best being the best okay
ser viendo al mejor siendo el mejor vale
there he is the
ya está
best feminist okay but then to
el el mejor feminista vale pero luego a
his girlfriend who is an insult beggar
su novia que el cual es insulto mendigo
he said a bunch of insults I don't
le dijo un montón de insultos no me
remember what insult he said to her but he
acuerdo cuál es insulto le dijo pero le
said a strong insult that the girlfriend could have
dijo insulto fuerte que la novia le pudo
filed a complaint speak
haber puesto una denuncia hable
ruined life comes
arruinado la vida viene
or rather and he told her that if it weren't for him she
o sea y le dijo que si no fuera por él
would be working in Madonna I
estaría trabajando en madonna ya
would like it was the best state of this
quisiera estuvo el mejor estado de esta
Christine and that she is doing much better than
christine y que le va mucho mejor que a
you
ti
but for the worse well I mean in some
pero para mal pues me refiero en algunos
ways in which women also
sentidos en los que la mujer también
have a favorable situation I believe in
tiene una situación favorable creo yo en
many not the desire does not sleep or that Hugo I do
muchas no el deseo no duerme o que hugo
not sleep and on top of that for free because if it
no duermo y encima gratis porque si no
weren't for your super chat in this
fuera por vuestro súper chat en este
live I was going to eat [ __ ] for what
directo me iba a comer una [__] por lo
is good [ __ ] did not eat me either
que es bueno una [__] tampoco me comió
what we are not going to leave the subject of what we
lo que no vamos a dejar el tema ya de lo
do with what we are not going to the
que hacemos con lo que no vamos a el
subject
tema
and obviously but but right now a
y obviamente pero pero ahora mismo una
situation of equality does not exist there is
situación de igualdad no existe hace
a lot to work on in
falta muchísimo en lo que trabajar en
both directions I think haha ​​the video
los dos sentidos creo yo jaja el vídeo
is going to work the best is going to  work
va a trabajar el mejor va a trabajar
so that there is equality
para que haya igualdad
okay he is going to work so that there is
vale él va a trabajar para que haya una
equality this takes a lot of work so it's
igualdad que esto tiene mucho curro así
good that it exists it's better to watch
que está bien que existe se mira mejor
the video of Rome look on youtube the
el vídeo de roma busca en youtube la
mind nothing done by the video because it
mente nada hecho por el vídeo porque lo
assumes it on facebook of lucido on facebook
asume a facebook de lucido en facebook
Rome but that I find out but when I
roma pero que me entera pero cuando he
saw that it is an hour and it is four
visto que es una hora y son las cuatro
in the morning I was able to look at base that I am not
de la mañana podido mirar base que no
going to see the best and even the
voy a ver el mejor y hasta lo
reactionary anyway if
reaccionario de todas maneras si acaso
tomorrow we go direct and we have nothing
mañana semos directo y no tenemos otra
else then we see Rome's response it is done
cosa pues vemos la respuesta de roma ya
or if you want we see Rome's response we
está o si queréis vemos la respuesta de
see Rome's response it is done
roma vemos la respuesta de roma ya está
but first I am going to see what
pero primero voy a ver lo que ha hecho
the best has done I mean you can't
el mejor
just go and
o sea no puedes simplemente ir y
ask what exactly ask
preguntar en qué exactamente preguntar
how come no but let's see how come no
cómo que no pero vamos a ver cómo que no
if you are at a demonstration
si tú estás en una manifestación
claiming rights and equality
reivindicando los derechos y la igualdad
then I go and ask you let's see tell me
pues yo cojo y te pregunto a ver dime
without you expecting it you are supposed to be
sin que te lo esperes se supone que
clear about why they are
tienes que tener claro porque se están
demonstrating okay like no like no like no they
manifestando vale como que no como que
can't go to the question
no como que no pueden ir a la pregunta
in what
en qué
on the contrary if you so so much want to
al contrario si tan tan tanto quieres
give a voice so much want to give a voice to the
darle voz tanto quiere darle voz a la
inequality and all things where there is
desigualdad y a todas las cosas la que
inequality damn take advantage take advantage of
hay desigualdad [__] aprovecha aprovecha
Rome's showcase specific data
el escaparate de roma' datos concretos
on CO2
de co2
men women having the same salary
el hombre la mujer tener mismo salario
is mandatory it would not be illegal in the
es obligatorio no sería ilegal a
Canary Islands positive discrimination of
canarias discriminación positiva de las
positions equality you prefer that a
posiciones igualdad prefieres de que una
woman has an advantage a position or
mujer tiene ventaja una posición o el
style things are not good but neither
estilo no está bien las cosas pero ni
for good nor for bad me that thanks
para bien ni para mal yo eso gracias
welcome look man what a shame that the
bienvenido fijaros tío qué pena que el
million made a reaction to the video
millón hizo una reacción al vídeo de
when the video I made when the
cuando el vídeo que hice cuando el
insult to the one that tim and did not even make a
insulto a la que tim y ni hizo una
reaction but I don't know why he deleted it from
reacción pero no sé por qué lo borro de
tweets I could no longer see it and no one
tweets ya no lo pude ni ver ni nadie lo
recorded it or anything man I would have loved to
grabó ni nada tío me hubiera encantado
see what he said to me
ver qué me decía
and I tell you I think that in many ways
y os lo digo creo que en muchos sentidos
women have a position favorable
las mujeres tiene una posición favorable
to men and vice versa it is something that
al hombre y viceversa ya es algo que
simply compensates that in some
simplemente se compensa que en algunos
senses of the life of man since you have
sentidos de la vida del hombre ya que te
new advantages and others the woman to have
nuevas ventajas y otros la mujer a tener
other advantages but right now
otras ventajas pero ahora mismo
definitely equality equality in
definitivamente igualdad igualdad en
many ways there is no I could give a
muchos sentidos no hay podría dar un
very clear example with twitch but I
ejemplo muy claro con twitch pero no
can't give the new because god created
puedo dar lo nuevo porque el dios creó
the best and then the monkey do
al mejor y después al mono
not disrespect it is not that type of
no faltes el respeto no es ese tipo de
insults not really  It was a
insultos no de verdad se ha hecho un
bit funny but no no it's not possible okay do
poco de gracia pero no no se puede vale
n't be like that
no seáis como tal
maybe they'll cancel me say it let's see there's
puede ser que me cancelen dilo a ver hay
an example but why wouldn't they
un ejemplo pero por qué no te van a
cancel you
cancelar
then you're a good that gives and don't say what
entonces eres un bien que da y no dicen
the best thinks
lo que piensa el mejor
and that's what they think say it very clearly with the
y así lo piensa dilo muy claro con el
tweet support but I'm not going to touch on this topic
tuit support pero este tema no voy a
but we could give an example of it is
tocar pero podríamos dar un ejemplo de
much easier to make a living
es muchísimo más fácil ganarse la vida
in tweets being a woman than being a man
en tweets siendo mujer que siendo hombre
because Javier thank you very much because
porque javier muchas gracias porque
what he's trying to say where I
lo que está queriendo decir donde
contact Riis face to face for telegram
contacto a la cara riis para telegram
well look at Karime and something you here please
pues mira a karime y algo tú aquí por fa
where does it want them to contact you face to
por donde quiere que te contacten a la
face and it relieves me to give it to some of the
cara y me alivia la darle a algunos de
trusted ones or rather what he's
los de confianza o sea lo que está
trying to say is that if you're a
queriendo decir es que tú si eres una
woman then just show up you put on a low
mujer pues simplemente llega te pones un
neckline and that's it
escote y ya está
guatafán the best it's not that simple
guatafán el mejor no es tan sencillo
I know many girls I know many
conozco a muchas chicas conozco a muchas
girls who don't triumph because of pets
chicas que no andan triunfa por mascotas
that they put on it's very
que se pongan
clear what happens is that it's
está clarísimo lo que pasa que es
much more difficult to get to a
muchísimo más difícil llegar a una
position even very clear being a woman
posición hasta clarísimos siendo mujer
than being a man that it compensates but
que siendo hombre que se compensa pero
what the [ __ ] I mean literally not
qué [__] o sea literalmente no
literally  no it has nothing to do with it it
literalmente no no tiene nada que ver
has to do with talent and
tiene que ver con el talento y
entertaining people no matter how good you are there
entretener a la gente por muy buena que
are a lot of girls I know a
estés hay un montón de chicas yo conozco
lot of girls who have
montón de chicas que hay que que se han
worn low cut provocative clothing and they are
puesto escote ropa provocativa y se
dedicated to the pen has fallen here on
dedican a se ha caído el boli aquí en la
camera and they are not like [ __ ] [ __ ] not
cámara y no sean como una [__] [__] ni
in you know you know there are any in fact
en you know you know hay alguna de hecho
none not in tui or anywhere it
ninguno ni en tui ni ninguna parte
has nothing to do with it I mean are you
no tiene nada que ver o sea me estás
telling me that by your rule of three the
diciendo que por tu regla de tres las
number one streamers of tweets would be
streamer número uno de tweets serían
women and they are not number one is
mujeres y no lo son el número uno es
euro
euro
if I'm not mistaken she follows him and goes and if I'm not
si no me equivoco le sigue y va y si no
mistaken the blond follows him
me equivoco le sigue el rubios
and he is followed by many
y le siguen muchos
who is the most viewed woman Christina and
cuál es la mujer más vista christina y
perhaps
quizás
who is the woman with the most vigor
cuál es la mujer con más vigor
there you have wind and no matter how many low cuts she
ahí tenéis a wind y que por más escotes
wears, more of a woman she is and more
que se ponga en más mujer que sea y más
than she dances for ten minutes straight
que baile durante diez minutos seguidos
the postage is
el franqueo
sunk
esta está hundida
or rather one thing with the other it is not
o sea una cosa con la otra no sea
widely there are many more women who
ampliamente hay muchas más mujeres que
can earn money on twitch than
pueden ganar dinero en twitch que
men and in a simple way but
hombres y de forma sencilla pero
probably there is not a single woman
probablemente no hay ni una sola mujer
in the top 10 of  tweets streamers are already
en el top 10 de tweets streamers ya son
things that favor the genders in
son cosas que favorecen a los géneros en
some sense it has
algún sentido
not made a point what he
no ha tenido un punto sentido lo que ha
said I have just been reminded to see those
dicho se me acaba de recordar a ver los
who see the lollipop you know that we have
que veis la piruleta sabéis que hemos
talked about him sometimes the friend who is going
hablado alguna vez de él el amigo que va
to defend Jesus on the island of
a defender a jesús en la isla de las
temptations that does not know how to speak that
tentaciones que no sabe hablar que todo
not everyone can go on tv when I
el mundo no puede ir a la tele cuando yo
go the day that the day that I go if they
vaya el día que el día que yo vaya si me
ever catch me from a reality show or something like
cogen alguna vez de algún reality o algo
that and I have to take someone to
de eso y tenga que llevar a alguien para
defend myself I do not know who I am going to take I would
defender me no sé a quién voy a llevar
take for not be some friend who has
llevaría por no sea alguna amiga que
presence that knows how to speak but the one
tenga presencia que sepa hablar pero es
who defends Jesus
que al que defiende a jesús
his argument is this yes because it
su argumento es éste sí porque se lo
can be because if not it is not because what is not is not
puede ser porque si no no es porque lo
so much it was because he knows
que no es no es tanto era porque él sabe
or I do not think I admit and then the best kiss
o no creo admito y después al mejor beso
is better he
está mejor
is a person you know the typical person
es una persona sabéis la típica persona
who takes it better not all men
que lleva mejor no todos los hombres
donate straws to women
hacemos donación pajilla a las mujeres
some of us do it to javi called
algunos se la hacemos al javi llamado
I teach how to walk or since he assumed that I am
enseño como pasear o ya que asumió que
not going to earn money here in any
no voy a ganar dinero aquí en ningún
live okay yes because what is what is
directo vale sí porque lo que es lo que
not a hero  because when I said the
no héroe porque cuando yo lo dije lo
same thing I told him the other time I said
mismo que le dije la otra vez lo dije no
you didn't understand but I said it like that what was
te enteraste pero lo dije así que lo
said said is like that speak well the
dicho dicho está así habla pues el
million just said something like that
millón acaba de decir algo así sin
nonsense yeah let's see women are the ones who
sentido sí a ver las mujeres son las que
have it easier to squeeze it in
más fácil lo tienen para apretarlo en
tweets but of course in the top 10 tweets there are no
tweets pero claro en el top 10 de tweets
women
no hay ninguna mujer
so of course it compensates
entonces claro compensa
that
qué
on the street at night well it
por la calle de noche bueno
's true okay what a woman when it comes to
es cierto vale lo de que una mujer a la
moving alone on the street doesn't
hora de moverse sola por la calle no
have the same ease as a man
tiene la misma facilidad que un hombre
okay a person with takes advantage of it is
vale a una persona con aprovecha para es
one thing what the girl has done here with
una cosa lo que ha hecho la chica aquí
tweets streamers has already surpassed she hasn't
de tweets streamers ya superó no ha
said much back she doesn't listen to me
dicho mucho para atrás no me escucha
after the million that of that no the
tras el millón de que de que no la
literal wage gap there is no need to
brecha salarial literal no hay que
demonstrate for that in a
manifestarse por eso en una
feminist demonstration literally in
manifestación feminista literalmente en
Spain it has been illegal for a long
españa ya es ilegal desde hace mucho
time also okay that a woman in the
tiempo además vale que una mujer en el
same job as a man
mismo puesto de trabajo que un hombre
earns differently that is illegal that is
cobre en diferente eso es ilegal eso es
discrimination but that a woman earns
discriminación pero que una mujer cobre
differently a man that a person of
diferente un hombre que una persona de
one race earns differently than another that a
una raza cobre diferente a otra que una
person earns differently than another because of
persona cobre diferente a otra por el
being a woman of being of another race or to
hecho de ser mujer de ser de otra raza o
say any other condition is illegal
decir cualquier otra condición es ilegal
in every way  the world I imagine I don't know
en todo el mundo me imagino que no sé
why all countries have been the same
por qué todos los países nos han igual
it is advanced but it is illegal if you have
está avanzado pero es ilegal si tienes
in 'the if in some job or in some
en 'la si en algún trabajo o en alguna
company that you know they pay
empresa que ustedes conozcáis le pagan
a woman less than a man for the
menos a una mujer que a un hombre por él
job position and her hair falls out she
puesto de trabajo se le cae el pelo lo
reports it and her hair falls out
denuncia y se le cae el pelo
or so what the [ __ ] are they fighting for the
o sea que [__] están luchando por las
but although you don't have to speak out it
pero aunque no te tienes que manifestar
is already illegal
que ya es ilegal
and this reminds me and of Montero the other
y esto me recuerda y de montero el otro
but my opinion no matter how good
pero mi opinión por muy buena que esté
the star is mero no matter how much she teaches if I do
la estrella mero por mucho que enseñe si
n't like her content or the way she
no me gusta su contenido o la forma de
does it I don't follow her or watch her
hacerlo no la sigo ni la veo
and Montero the other day a
y montero el otro día
minister of a ministry that they had to
ministra de un ministerio que han tenido
invent to give her a job
que inventar para darle un trabajo
because that ministry is useless
porque ese ministerio no sirve para nada
said the other day to justify the 450
dice el otro día para justificar los 450
million that that ministry costs us she
millones que nos cuesta ese ministerio
told us that genital mutations should be penalized
nos dice habría que penalizar las
and virtually it has been illegal for
y virtualmente es ilegal desde hace
many years it is punishable by law so
muchísimos años está penado por la ley o
at least she
sea que por lo menos le le le le te
hired an advisor with those 450
contrató a un asesor con esos 450
million that the ministry costs to
millones que cuesta el ministerio
hire an advisor to go over the
contratar un asesor que te repase el
script for you before  of talking about
guión antes de hablar
walking alone on the street at night and well it
andar sola por la calle de noche y bueno
's true okay the thing about a woman when it
es cierto vale lo de que una mujer a la
comes to moving alone on the street doesn't
hora de moverse sola por la calle no
have the same ease as a man
tiene la misma facilidad que un hombre
okay it's normal they have to be more
vale es es normal han de ir con más
careful it's a reality the question is
cuidado es una realidad la cuestión es
that some of that can change with the
que puede cambiar algo de eso con el
feminist movement in the aforementioned
movimiento feminista en el mencionado
plan there are already some sound laws that prohibit
plan ya hay unas leyes sound prohíben a
any man from doing bad things
cualquier hombre hacer las cosas malas
exactly it's wide what we have to do the
exacto es ancho lo que hay que hacer el
best is to vote for a party that
mejor es votar a un partido que
toughens these laws
endurezca esas leyes
firm hand
mano dura
not for soft parties
no a partidos blanditos
any person on the street no matter how much
cualquier persona por la calle por mucho
you complain is going to change adores
que te quejes va a cambiar adores
sense no I don't think so you know it's something that already
sentido no no creo sabes es algo que ya
exists that argument is x from there more
está ese argumento es x de ahí más altos
night stops for men than women are not there
nocturnos a hombres que a mujeres no
that doesn't exist it's the story I
están que no existe es el cuento es
mean that more men are exposed at
decir que se expongan más hombres a
certain hours of the night and there end up
ciertas horas de la noche y acaben
being more assaults on men than
habiendo más asaltos a hombres que a
women it
mujeres
could be but simply because there is
puede ser pero simplemente porque hay
more exposure on the part of men and
más exposición por parte del hombre y
probably the assaults that are on
probablemente los asaltos que sean a
women will be the majority of them
mujeres serán la mayoría de ellos
rapes and on men it's not worth it so it
violaciones y a hombres no vale así que
's not an argument of x of you know and to the
no es un argumento de x de sabes y al
man I mean that happens because there are
hombre me refiero eso pasa porque hay
people who are disgusting okay  but the
gente que es asquerosa vale pero la
people who are not going to exist their whole
gente que no se va a existir toda la
[ __ ] lives what we need to do is
[__] vida lo que hay que hacer es
toughen the sentences okay the
endurecer las condenas vale en el
moment they start to fall really really really really
momento que empiecen a caer bien bien
strong okay and security in
bien bien fuerte vale y la seguridad en
the streets or that crime goes down yeah yeah
la calle o que baje la delincuencia ya
see this how crime is going down much more
ya ver esto cómo va bajando mucho más la
sometimes she thinks about it a lot of
delincuencia a veces lo piensa mucho
[ __ ] [ __ ] the general attitude is
de [__] [__] la actitud en general es
more social but this girl is not speaking well
más social pero no está hablando bien
also I mean it could be
esta chica también es decir puede ser
more of a social movement than a
más un movimiento social más que un
general movement where you want to
movimiento en general donde quieres
change certain laws the issue of machismo is
cambiar ciertas leyes tema del machismo
still something present in
sigue siendo algo presente en la
society regardless of whether it is
sociedad independientemente de que sea
something legal good there is no need for
algo legal el bien no hace falta que
a law that goes against
haya una ley que vaya en contra de la
women for there to be inequality no no it
mujer para que haya una desigualdad no
is not a bad argument like I see
no es no es un mal argumento en plan veo
a better argument from this girl than the
un mejor argumento de esta chica que el
previous one
de la anterior
in this interview you can see that many do not
en esta entrevista se ve que muchas no
know what it is about in the reel and that
saben de qué va la cosa en el reel y eso
is a video to go and make
es un vídeo para ir a dejar mal a las
other people look bad it
otras personas
others look bad they make themselves look
otros se dejan mal ellas
bad they
se dejan mal ellas
plant from the same video asking
planta desde el mismo vídeo preguntando
people who go against the
a gente que va en contra del movimiento
feminist movement they adhered  like some [ __ ]
feminista adherían como unos [__]
[ __ ] people have also interviewed
subnormales también se ha entrevistado a
me, the best thing is to set up an interview with me
mí el mejor arme una entrevista tú a mí
with technical questions, Almela, let's see
con preguntas técnicas almela a ver
who comes off as [ __ ], it
quién queda como subnormal
's the same kind of questions, it's not a
es la misma clase de preguntas no es un
big enough argument.
argumento suficientemente grande
I'm going to discredit the
voy a desacreditar el movimiento
feminist movement of March 8th by going to ask
feminista del 8m yendo a preguntar
four or five technical things. No, no, I don't
cuatro o cinco cosas técnicas no no no
think that's correct, technical thing, be
creo que sea correcto cosa técnica sea
literal, he's asking you, let's see,
literal le está preguntando a ver
explain to me where you see inequality,
explícame dónde ven la desigualdad cosas
technical things. Yes, well,
técnicas sí bueno
a graduate with a
un graduado
higher degree has had to study
un grado superior ha tenido que estudiar
clothes to think about this for three
ropa para pensarse esta durante tres
years, he has been studying very, very, very
años ha estado estudiando bien bien bien
well, these super technical questions,
bien estas preguntas super técnicas
what questions would you ask them if the question
qué preguntas les harías si la cuestión
is not bad questions, but if you have
no son malas preguntas pero si tienes
the ways in which they are asked, how
las formas en las que se hacen el cómo
and that the client, in other words, they are
y que el cliente o sea que son preguntas
technical questions to make the other party look bad,
técnicas para dejar mal a la otra parte
but they are not bad questions, the question
pero no son malas preguntas la cuestión
is how the ways are done, but things are being
es cómo se hacen las formas pero cosas
done, but if it is being done
está haciendo pero si se está haciendo
politely, no, I
educadamente no
mean, how do you want me to do it?
o sea cómo quiere que la haga
You try to discredit what they say
intentas desacreditar lo que dicen
simply by saying things like
simplemente diciendo cosas como que
statistics or I don't know what that approach to
estadísticas o no sé que ese planteo a
them, between a [ __ ] person on
los entre estando una [__] persona por
the street, crazy, to say there and discredit
la calle loco decir ahí y desacreditar
an argument  what he said saying but
un argumento que ha dicho diciendo pero
if it doesn't discredit anything he just
si no desacredita nada ya sólo le
asks and doesn't know how to answer because they
pregunta y no sabe qué responder porque
don't even know what they're claiming or
no saben ni lo que están reivindicando o
what statistics it's a little bit a little bit it
que estadísticas es un poco un poco nos
seems to us that it's a little bit it's a little bit xv
parece que es un poco es un poco xv
[Laughs] it's
[Risas]
a little bit he says it's a little bit
es un poco dice él
Nahuel thank you very much it's a little bit x
es un poco nahuel muchas gracias es un
in fact okay okay it's a little bit
poco equis de hecho vale vale
xv I don't know don't ask me it's a
es un poco xv no sé no me pregunte es un
little bit it will go bad even in Latin America there is no
poco lo irá mal hasta el latam no hay
machismo whether you're a man or a woman they'll shoot you I
machismo seas hombre o mujer te fríen a
love you Latinos to defend the
tiros os quiero latinos para defender lo
indefensible no I don't agree
indefendible no yo no estoy de acuerdo
with many of the forms of the
con muchas de las formas del movimiento
feminist movement I mean really yes or yes you
feminista es decir de verdad si o si os
think that there is like equality you
pensáis que hay como una igualdad tú
know what happens is that the best looking at them and
sabes que pasa que el mejor mirándolos y
seeing and he's the typical one who in reality I don't
viendo y es el típico que en realidad no
believe a [ __ ] thing in what he's
creo una [__] [__] en lo que está
saying in what he's defending right
diciendo en lo que está defendiendo
now I don't believe a [ __ ] thing he's
ahora mismo no creo una [__] [__] lo
doing everything so that they don't put him in
está haciendo todo para que no le ponen
and to look good okay man you have to be
y por quedar bien vale tío hay que ser
clear with what you think and maybe bad
claro con lo que piensas y tal malo sea
but the best no no he doesn't support a [ __ ]
pero el mejor no no no apoya una [__]
thing the feminist movement
[__] al movimiento feminista
okay no rum support a [ __ ] [ __ ]
vale no ron apoye una [__] [__]
is to look good and period literally it's
es para quedar bien y punto literal soy
me when I liked to change it was what they
yo cuando me gustaba cambiar era lo que
told me was fine but it doesn't quite add up to me it does
me decían que estaba bien pero no me
n't quite add
termina de cuadrar no me termina de
up to me because literally seeing the
cuadrar pues literalmente viendo al
million identified is how I hate it get out
millón identificado es como lo odio sal
of there the reality is that it is noticeable in your
de ahí la realidad es que se nota en tus
words that you are not at all convinced of what you
palabras que no está nada convencido de
say
lo que dices
the literal one does not think a [ __ ] about what she
la literal no piensa una [__] lo que
is saying hahaha this manga hahaha
está diciendo jajajaja este manga jajaja
rises from the hands zelaya de lion I do
se eleva de las manos zelaya de lion
n't know well the best is authentic
no sé bien queda el mejor sea auténtico
and that really after women have been
y que realmente después de que la mujer
screwed for centuries and
haya estado puteada desde siglos y
centuries and centuries and centuries they do not have the
siglos y siglos y siglos no tengan
right to have a day and on top of that you have to
derecho a tener un día y encima os
go laugh at them you are a
tengáis que ir a reír de ellas estáis un
little wrong you are a little a
poco equivocado os estáis un poco un
little wrong not only is there
poco equivocados no solamente hay
discrimination still no I do not think there is
discriminación aún no no creo que haya
any need to go touch her support
ninguna necesidad de ir a tocar la apoya
in the 8 it is not bad to give a day but
en el 8 no está mal dar un día pero la
women are sexist
mujer es machista
people in the chalet want to choose
la gente en el chalet quiere escoger
in Europe a statistic that looks at it if there is
en europa una estadística que lo mira si
a statistic that measures how sexist
hay una estadística que mide lo machista
people are exactly then
que es la gente exactamente entonces en
based on what is known
base a que se sabe
then based on  why is that
entonces en base a qué
why a test is up your ass and it tells you the
por eso un test por el culo y te pone el
percentage of machismo you have inside
porcentaje de machismo que tienes dentro
what nonsense is that but then
qué tontería es esa pero entonces en
based on what is the argument
base a que es el argumento
based on your brown egg since your
en base a tu huevo moreno ya que te lo
twitter allies tell you
dicen los aliados de twitter
the civil servants links or generate
las funcionarias enlaces o generar tías
sexist chicks you are stupid what is the reality
machista eres tonto que es la realidad
plan one is telling her that there is
plan uno le está diciendo que existe un
machismo in our society there is still
machismo en nuestra sociedad hay aún
a lot of machismo there is a lot of
muchísimo machismo hay un montón de
discrimination against women it does not have to
discriminación a la mujer no tiene por
be something that is written in a law
qué ser algo que esté escrito en una ley
where a woman is legally discriminated against
donde se discrimine de forma legal a una
and the other is telling her and there are
mujer y le está diciendo el otro y
any statistics on that it is
existe alguna estadística de eso es
stupid natural that there are
tonto natural de que exista una
statistics on that I vote because [ __ ] me
estadística de eso voto porque me jodas
the geek is from the vine
el friki es de la vid
[Music]
[Música]
stupid you can't go to a [ __ ]
estúpido no puedes ir a una [__]
demonstration and ask a
manifestación y preguntarle a una
person for an exact statistic and I don't
persona una estadística exacta y yo no
see it a little exaggerated I mean how
lo veo un poco exagerado es decir como
culturally the putter can't be it is
culturalmente el putter no puede ser es
the basis of your video
la base de tu vídeo
that is the link I know it is the link of
ese es el link sé que es el link de
eighth note singing the opening that night
corchea cantando el opening esa noche
of the year when already w of jj fer I already know what
del año cuando ya w de jj fer ya sé cuál
the video is what is true is  that
es el vídeo lo que sí es cierto es que
places are reserved for women in
se reservan plazas para mujeres en
public competitions to do the same
oposiciones públicas para hacer el mismo
job, I do not agree with
trabajo yo no estoy de acuerdo con
certain advantages, that is to say the typical thing of
ciertas ventajas es decir lo típico de
forcing there to be the same number of
forzar a que haya la misma cantidad de
men and women in the same
hombres y mujeres en un mismo puesto de
job, always then a little
trabajo a siempre luego un poco
exaggerated, yes, it is true that hiring
exagerado sí que es verdad que contratar
a woman from the point of view of
a una mujer desde el punto de vista de
an employer in some cases can be
un empresario en algunos casos puede ser
counterproductive, especially because of the
contraproducente no sobre todo por el
issue of sick leave, x amount of time per
tema de bajas laborales equis tiempo al
month, menstruation, like potentially
mes regla en plan potencialmente
pregnancies, there is more risk in hiring
embarazos tiene más riesgo contratar a
a woman, you know, and I understand that when it comes
una mujer sabes y entiendo pues que a la
to hiring a woman, for
hora de contratar a una mujer pues para
a businessman, businesswoman, it is much
un empresario empresaria pues sea mucho
more of a risk of being a social, not a
más riesgo de ser un cambio social no
political change. I agree with them, I
político estoy de acuerdo con los
think it is more of a social problem
creo que es más un problema social más
than a legal one, blank, to do better, he is
que legal en blanco hacer mejor te está
telling you that he as a businessman would not
diciendo que él como empresario no
hire and understand that he would not
contrataría y entiende que no
hire and understand that whoever does it
contrataría y entienda el que lo hace a
asks a woman, would do it before a man
una mujer pide haría ante a un hombre
literally, you
literal
do not believe in [ __ ] feminism, he does not
no crees en el [__] feminismo no lo
defend it, it is [ __ ] feminism and I see it as
defiende es el [__] feminismo y lo veo
fine that he does not defend it, but do not try to
bien que no lo defienda pero no intentes
pretend that if perhaps there are laws that in
aparentar que si quizás hay leyes que en
some way benefit women more,
algún sentido benefician más a la mujer
perhaps others that  that benefit men more
quizá otras que benefician más al hombre
and that's difficult, I wonder what
y eso que es difícil me me pregunto qué
law benefits men more, I
ley beneficia más al hombre
wonder can someone give me an
me pregunto alguien me puede dar un
example,
ejemplo
what law? I can give you examples of
qué ley yo te puedo poner ejemplos de
laws that benefit women more, okay,
leyes que beneficien más a la mujer vale
can someone please tell me if the
me puede por favor alguien decir si el
best one is going to give an example now
mejor ahora va a dar algún ejemplo
because he's not going to give it to him, it's simply
porque no lo va a dar a él simplemente
based on, I mean, the things that
se basa es decir las cosas que están
feminists are saying on twitter, no, like that,
diciendo la feminista en twitter no así
women have
es que las mujeres am
been screwed over for many years and
han estado puteada durante muchos años y
so now they have to be
entonces ahora pues tienen que es ser
superior to men and men are
superior al hombre y los hombres son
potential rapists since graffiti, that's it
potenciales violadores desde graffé ya
and get to a point where
está y llegar a un punto lo que todo el
everyone agrees on the laws that
mundo esté de acuerdo en las leyes que
are quite passable in Spain, I don't
son como bastante pasables en españa no
think there will be good nights today, don't
creo que hayan buenas noches hoy no
put the members chat for today, just
pones el chat de miembros para hoy basta
a quick live stream, we'll go right now, in
un directo rapidito ya mismo nos vamos
fact, like, very, very, very exaggerated, but
de hecho como muy muy muy exagerado pero
where thanks to
donde gracias a discriminaciones
social discrimination, closed groups of
sociales grupos cerrados de
conversations about deals in
conversaciones de tratos en ambientes de
work environments is where you really see
trabajo es donde realmente se ve un
machismo, the white and york, let's
machismo el blanco y york
feel if you just invented it or it has been
que sienta si os acaba de inventar o se
done in social groups, closed groups, I
ha hecho en grupos sociales grupos
really see discrimination against women
realmente veo discriminación a la mujer
in my day to day life  I see it on twitch I see it
en mi día a día lo veo en twitch lo veo
in closed work environments on the
en ambientes de trabajo cerrados por la
street I see it in nightclub environments
calle lo veo en ambientes de discoteca
but oh well what happened in rivers ballet in a
pero bueno lo que pasó en ríos ballet en
nightclub environment literal literal na
ambiente de discoteca literal literal na
wewe thank you very much literal video I don't know
wewe muchas gracias literal vídeo no sé
if maybe it never came out in your [ __ ]
si es que a lo mejor no salió en tu [__]
life
vida
Javier is a close one I admire you a lot
javier es un cierra te admiro un montón
thank you very much Frank literally the
muchas gracias frank literal los
nightclub environments women
ambientes de discoteca las mujeres
get into the nightclub for free at best it
entran gratis en la discoteca al mejor
costs men two thousand pesetas
a los hombres le cuesta dos mil pesetas
and I think a little what I did man is
y yo piensa un poco lo que hice tío es
where it ended up having an ultra mega
donde acabó teniendo una ultra mega
controversy because in their offices there was
polémica porque en sus oficinas había
sexual harassment and there was
acoso sexual y había en general
discrimination against women in general and they ended up coming
discriminación a las mujeres y acabaron
out I don't know ten or fifteen women
saliendo qué sé yo diez o quince mujeres
from riot who were fed up with
de riot que estaban hasta la [__] de
having to go to the offices and that every now and
tener que ir a las oficinas y que cada
then they were making
dos por tres estuvieran haciendo bromas
sexist jokes or they were simply
machistas o estuvieran simplemente
discriminating against these things plan it may
discriminando las estas cosas plan puede
be more or less true okay never never
ser más o menos cierto vale nunca nunca
really how from what you can know no
realmente lo como por lo puedes saber no
what happens inside inside a place to
lo que pasa dentro de dentro de un sitio
which you don't have access is very probable
al cual no tienes acceso es muy probable
and it is something that is probably real
y es algo que es probable que sea real
but damn socially I think that
pero ostia plan socialmente creo que la
women are still strongly discriminated against
mujer sigue fuertemente discriminada de
again it is not about whether  the boy you are a
nuevo no se trata de si el chico eres
girl when it comes to defending an argument
chica a la hora de defender un argumento
I mean it's about being a little
me refiero se trata de ser un poco
coherent and if you get out of the house a little
coherente y si tú sales un poco de casa
dude if you see a little the interest
tío si tú ves un poco las interés
social interactions that
interacciones sociales que tiene la
people have is worth the difference in how certain
gente vale la diferencia como ciertas
people treat a man or treat a
personas tratan a un hombre o trata una
woman or in some ways it really
mujer o algunos sentidos realmente
exists but who does that why
existe pero quién hace eso por qué
is that an [ __ ] there is
eso es un capullo
discrimination there is a
existe una discriminación que existe una
very large number of people who treat
cantidad muy grande de gente que trata
a person less for the fact of
de menos a una persona por el hecho de
being a woman then that person is an
ser mujer entonces esa persona es un
[ __ ] of course there are many
[__] claro que sí existen muchos
[ __ ] in the world but there are
[__] en el mundo pero hay
[ __ ] men [ __ ] women no there won't be
[__] hombre [__] mujeres no
more and there will be women who are
no habrá más y habrá mujeres que sean
racist for example there won't be women
racistas por ejemplo no habrá mujeres
who are racist well there will be I don't know
que sean racistas pues habrá que no sé
each person who is an [ __ ] and who is
cada persona el que sea [__] y el
[ __ ] is
que se han [__] lo es
if you want to see it or not is
si quieres o no quieres verlo es cosa
your business look the thing is this is an
tuya mira es que esto es una mentalidad
extremely common mentality and when I
extremadamente común y cuando yo
extremely common it's something that
extremamente común es algo que la
most of you have probably at
mayoría de vosotros probablemente en
some point thought it has said it
algún momento lo ha pensado lo ha dicho
and you have it so ingrained inside you that you
y lo tenéis tan metido dentro que lo
see it as something normal you see a guy and he
veis algo normal vosotros veis un tío y
tells you I've been with ten girls
os comenta he estado con diez chicas
this week  you know what the
esta semana sabéis cuál es el
common thought is after hearing
pensamiento común después de escuchar
that tremendous machine how can it be so
eso tremendo máquina cómo puede ser tan
good what a [ __ ] madness right but then
bueno qué [__] locura no pero luego
you have the same the same phrase from a
tienes la misma la misma frase desde una
girl and most people in this
chica y la mayoría de personas en esta
society end up thinking what a tremendous
sociedad acaban pensando por tremenda
filth and they will comment on it in
[__] y lo comentarán en círculos
closed circles this kind of thinking in
cerrados esta clase de pensamiento de
itself is already a situation of d
por sí ya es una situación de d
don't make a mistake don't make a mistake
no te equivoques no te equivoques
don't make a mistake if you're saying that
no te equivoques si estás diciendo eso
because you will surely think it yourself it
porque seguramente lo pensarás tú
depends depends on the case
depende depende del caso
depends on the case there is one thing that must
depende del caso hay una cosa que hay
be clear and whoever says no that
que tenerla clara y el que diga que no
is not
así no es así
normally like that
normalmente
[Music] let's
[Música]
see how I explain this normally the
a ver cómo explico esto normalmente el
boy
chico
[Music]
[Música]
the girl in the one who chooses more if a
la chica en la que elige más a si una
girl wants
chica quiere
[Music] to
[Música]
flirt or rather wants to know how I say it
ligar o sea quiere saber cómo lo digo
if a girl wants to eat him she has it
si una chica quiere comérselo lo tiene
easier than the boy I do
más fácil que el chico
n't know if I explain myself
no sé si me explico
how I would explain you all this is
cómo explicaría ustedes esto está
literally it depends depends on the case depends on the
literalmente depende depende del caso
case
depende del caso
if you choose who loves you who you
si tú eliges a quien te quiere con quién
want to flirt with or rather one thing is a boy
quiere ligar o sea una cosa es un chico
okay
vale
if he sleeps with 10 he is not a
que si se acuesta con 10 no es un
winner because at  better if she's
triunfador porque a lo mejor se está
sleeping with 10 guys that week but she's
acostando con 10 en esa semana pero que
not being selective or
no está siendo ni selectivo ni que le
liking him or anything the guy is [ __ ] he's
guste ni nada el chico está cogiendo se
sleeping with the first guy he asks for no no he
está acostando con lo primero que pide
's not a winner okay and the
no no no es ningún triunfador vale y las
girls might as well be a winner if
chicas lo mismo será una triunfadora si
she slept with 10 guys that week
se acostaba con 10 chicos en esa semana
but they're 10 guys that she likes you
pero son 10 chicos que que le gustan
know so yes a winner I do
entiende entonces si una triunfadora
n't know if I'm explaining myself
no sé si me explico
how literally it seems super
como literalmente me parece super
old fashioned to me to think about
antiguo pensar eso
machismo in fact if there's a guy and
de machismo de hecho si hay un tío y de
thank you very much
muchas gracias
if there's a guy who's sleeping with
si hay un tío que se está acostando con
10 different ones at the same time then the
diez ya diferente a la vez pues la
truth is a little bit filthy to me you
verdad un poquito cerdo sí que me parece
know what I'm saying social is a
sabes lo que te digo social es una una
way of thinking that's extremely it depends on
forma de pensar extremadamente depende
the context not 20 sexist and like this
del contexto no 20 machista y como esta
kind of attitude and like this kind of
clase de actitud y como esta clase de
thinking there are many things little by
pensamiento hay muchísimas cosas poco a
little they know how to change and go out educating
poco sabe ir cambiando y salir educando
people better and continue thinking
mejor a la gente y seguir pensando
differently okay what makes me
diferente vale a mí no me lo que me da
angry is that because there are [ __ ] agents
rabia es que porque hay agentes
championing and appropriating the
[__] abanderado y apropiándose del
movement they end up dirtying it like the
movimiento lo acabe ensuciando como la
political class I'm  I 100% agree, I do not
clase política estoy 100% acuerdo yo no
agree with how
estoy de acuerdo con cómo se está
the feminist movement is being carried out and
llevando el movimiento feminista y
probably the promoters you say are
probablemente los promo dices tú están
former standard bearers of feminism blah blah blah
ex abanderados del feminismo bla bla bla
saying these turbo mega offended people who
decir estos turbo mega ofendidos que se
dedicate themselves to making threads on twitter to
dedican a hacer hilos en twitter a
literally get offended by anything that
literal ofenderse por cualquier cosa que
happens if it has happened to a woman
pasa si le ha pasado a una mujer
regardless of whether it is because of the fact of
independientemente si es por el hecho de
being a woman or not they speak up they jump at the
ser una mujer o no hablan saltan a la
slightest thing
mínima
these people dirty the
esa gente ensucia al movimiento
feminist movement I 100% agree with that
feminista estoy 100% de acuerdo con ello
to solve a problem we have to
para solucionar un problema hay que
detect its causes
detectar sus causas
the forum itself is politicized to an
el foro mismo está politizado hasta un
extreme where it does not matter if it helps women or not the
extremo donde no importa si ayuda o no a
only thing that matters is generating tension
la mujer sólo importa generar crispación
and obtaining money and publicity or in
y obtener dinero y publicidad o en
some parties
algunos partidos
I agree the way we can we can
estoy de acuerdo del modo podemos
think we can and think they have
podemos pensar podemos y pensar se han
taken over the feminist movement it
adueñado del movimiento feminista que
seems that they are the only ones who look out for
parece que son los únicos que miran por
women for
las mujeres por los derechos de las
women's rights of the groups that for
mujeres de los colectivos de que para
these groups to believe that their
que esos colectivos se crean que su
party is that okay and that's it and deceives
partido es ese vale y ya está y engaña a
many people there are many people who
muchísima gente hay muchísima gente que
are like that it seems like a superpower and then they are
son así parece superpoder y luego están
seeing that within the party there are
viendo que dentro del partido hay
sexist attitudes there  attitudes worse
actitudes machistas hay actitudes peores
than even other councilors
que la de incluso otros concejales de
good to other politicians from other
bueno a otros políticos de otros
parties that they consider sexist
partidos que ellos consideran machistas
no but they turn a blind eye when they
no pero se hacen la vista gorda cuando
happen within that party they turn a
pasan dentro de ese partido se hacen la
blind eye because because that party
vista gorda porque porque ese partido se
has taken over that by of that movement
ha adueñado de ese por de ese movimiento
as if it were the only party that
como si fuera el único partido que
defends that group and the only one that is doing
defiende ese colectivo y el único que le
well
va bien
and then turn a blind eye when
y entonces hacer la vista gorda cuando
discriminatory movements happen
pasan movimientos discriminatorios
within that party with people and
dentro de ese partido con gente y
politicians from that party they make eat that they have
políticos de ese partido hacen comer que
not seen know
no la han visto saber
Elisa ar very funny the
elisa ar mucha gracia el movimiento
feminist movement is very badly carried out to throw
feminista está muy mal llevado a echar
my argument is not as ultra
yo mi argumento no es tampoco como ultra
pro feminist I am saying that
pro feminista yo estoy diciendo de que
a fight for equality is really still needed I
realmente hace falta aún una lucha por
think that we are quite
la igualdad creo que estamos bastante
far from going in the right direction there are
lejos de ir por un buen camino hay
some cases in which obviously
algunos casos en los que obviamente la
women have certain advantages okay it is
mujer tiene ciertas ventajas vale es
real but it is not something that I am
real pero tampoco es algo en lo que yo
touching on I mean and also for
esté esté tocando es decir y también por
example to be no if it is to be a police officer or a
ejemplo para ser no si es policía o ser
firefighter
bombero
you have to pass some weaker physical tests
tienes que pasar unas pruebas físicas
if you are a woman plan there are
más flojas si eres mujer plan existen
those differences that I think
esas diferencias que creo que no
should not exist in some cases
deberían existir en algunos casos las
I see them as unnecessary
veo innecesarias
literally literally if you are a
literalmente literalmente si eres una
woman your body your genetics is  different, I
mujer tu cuerpo tu genética es diferente
mean, I imagine that will be in
o sea me imagino yo que eso estará
place,
puesto
that will be in place so that it is an
eso estará puesto para que sea una cosa
equitable thing for me there doesn't have to be
equitativa para mí no tiene que haber
equality as such in everything, in some
igualdad como tal en todo en algunas
things there has to be equity that is
cosas tiene que haber equidad que es
different, you know, you're not going to put
diferente me entiende no le vas a poner
the same physical tests on a man
las mismas pruebas físicas a un hombre
as on a corpulent woman,
que a una mujer corpulenta mente por
genetically speaking, we are not equal,
genéticas no somos iguales
well that's it, but you can't, okay,
pues ya está pero no puedes vale
counterargue discrimination, let's talk about
contraargumentar una discriminación a
equality, let's not imagine, let's
ver hablemos de igualdad no imaginemos
imagine that there is
imaginemos que
a fire here right now, I have it all
que hay un incendio aquí ahora mismo
around me
tengo alrededor a tope
and there is a fire right now and
y hay un incendio ahora mismo y se quema
the whole entrance to my house is burning, okay, the house
toda la entrada de mi casa vale la casa
goes up in flames, more and more on fire and
sale en llamas cada vez más en llamas y
I lose consciousness and I fall
yo pierdo el conocimiento y me caigo
here behind me, okay, and then you all of a
aquí atrás vale y entonces ustedes
sudden call 911. Hey,
de repente llamáis al 112 oye que la
Javi Oliveira's house, there's
casa de javi oliveira en la casa de javi
a fire at Javi Oliveira's house, he had fallen
oliveira hay un fuego había caído el
conscious to the ground, we
consciente al suelo
have to call the fire department. Take the
hay que llamar a los bomberos [__] los
fire department with a crane and a ladder
bomberos con una grúa y con una escalera
and get in through the terrace, okay, they
y se meten por la terraza vale nos
have to take our arm out because we are
tienen que sacar el brazo que estamos
unconscious, me, my wife, and my two children,
inconsciente yo mi mujer y mis dos hijos
okay,
vale
who would come in for us? I weigh 90
quien entraría por nosotros yo peso 90
kilos almost worth who would come in for
kilos casi vale quien entraría por
us
nosotros
a woman
una mujer
or a man who can hold us in their
o un hombre que pueda acogernos en
arms
brazos
[Music]
[Música]
a man in a closet a pasture who
un hombre en un armario un potrero que
comes in through the terrace maybe a
entre por la terraza a lo mejor una
woman can do the job of a firefighter she
mujer puede hacer el trabajo de bombero
could also be putting out the fire and so
también puede estar apagando el fuego y
on no matter what no but to come in
demás no según qué no pero para entrar
here to come in here and have
aquí para entrar aquí dentro y tener
imagine that I but imagine that it's
imagínate que yo pero imagínate que es
my father who weighs a hundred and something
mi padre que es que pese a ciento y pico
kilos
de kilos
and is even taller than me and so
y mide todavía más que yo y así
my father throws on the floor who comes in
mi padre tira en el suelo quién entra
for my father a woman or a man a female
por mi padre una mujer o un hombre una
or male firefighter
bombera o un bombero
then then there has to be one
entonces entonces tiene que haber
hundred percent equality in everything it has to
igualdad al cien por cien en todo tiene
be equal the same physical tests the
que ser igual las mismas pruebas físicas
same jobs let's
los mismos puestos de trabajo
not be idiots let's not be
no seamos [__] no seamos
idiots there will be things
[__] habrá que abraca habrá cosas
like for example the law in which there has to be
como por ejemplo la ley en la que tenga
equality but there will be other
que haber igualdad pero habrá otras
things in which there has to be equity
cosas las que tenga que haber equidad
with this to say that they have some
con esto para decir que tengan algunas
legal advantages in some sense okay or
ventajas legales en algún sentido vale o
some social advantages in some
algunas ventajas sociales en algún
sense it doesn't mean that there isn't
sentido no quiere decir que no exista
a very strong discrimination I prefer
una fuertísima discriminación prefiero
that yes some of these things are
que sí que algunas de estas cosas son
counterproductive not to defend their
contraproducentes no para defender su
own movement it is clear at one
propio movimiento está claro en un
point that you do not rescue you
momento el que no hagas te rescata
would be very romantic what happens that
sería muy romántico qué pasa que no
strong women do not exist well let's see
existen mujeres fuertes pues a ver
surely there is some woman
seguramente exista alguna mujer
surely yes surely there is a
seguramente sí seguramente exista una
woman who can handle a 120
mujer que pueda con un hombre de 120
kilo man of course with my father if the
kilos claro con mi padre si se cae el
ground falls surely there will be some in the
suelo seguramente habrá alguna en el
world who can of course but in
mundo que pueda claro pero por lo
general I believe that by nature
general yo creo que por naturaleza los
men are bigger and stronger
hombres son más grandes y más fuertes
than women you are not talking
que las mujeres no estáis hablando no
we are not talking nonsense here it is that it is already by it is
estamos hablando tonterías aquí ya es
by nature by
que ya es por ya es por naturaleza de
nature no no it cannot there cannot be one
por naturaleza no no no puede no puede
hundred percent equality in the
haber igualdad al cien por cien en las
same jobs the same
mismas puestos de trabajo las mismas
characteristics not in jobs that are
características no en trabajos que son
physical or then three examples because it just occurred to
físicos o después tres ejemplo porque se
me but we could give
me acaba de ocurrir pero podríamos poner
any thousand examples that occur to us
cualquier mil ejemplos que se nos ocurra
but physically in physical jobs no you
pero físicamente en trabajos físicos no
cannot have everyone in the same
no se puede tener a todos en el mismo
job
puesto de trabajo
the senses have many advantages
los sentidos tienen muchas ventajas
over men then it is difficult it is not
sobre el hombre luego es difícil no es
simply the fact of coming and saying
simplemente el hecho de venir y decir
well then they discriminate against me equally
bueno pues que me discriminan igualmente
that if there continues to be that mentality of
que si sigue habiendo esa mentalidad de
superiority on the part of men in
superioridad por parte del hombre en
many ways I believe that
muchos sentidos yo creo que la igualdad
social equality has to change from the
social se tiene que cambiar desde las
roots, that is to say from the  basic education
raíces o sea desde la educación básica
that parents give to their children i think
que dar los padres a los hijos yo creo
that in many cases you're going to have the
que en muchos casos vas a tener el
typical violent father who hits his
típico padre violento que le pega a la
wife because in most cases you're going to
mujer porque en la mayoría de casos vas
have the typical man who hits his wife
a tener al típico hombre a la mujer no
let's not think that that's a very very
vamos a pensar de que eso es una minoría
very small minority let's think that
muy muy muy pequeña vamos a pensar que
yes no if you want equality stop
eso sí no si quieres igualdad deja de
giving priority to girls in
dar prioridad a las minitas en los
kw clinics
consultorios kw
the majority of girls don't tell for
la mayoría de chicas no cuentan por
fear of what happens to them and i think that
miedo a lo que les pasa y yo creo que
girls find it much easier to
las chicas tienen muchísimo más fácil el
talk about some type of abuse than
hablar sobre algún tipo de maltrato que
boys i see that and more in the way they
los chicos eso lo veo y más en la forma
are on
en la que están a la misma redes
social networks just like right now it's
sociales igual que si ahora mismo es
literally what's in fashion if
literalmente lo que está de moda que si
something has happened to you to tell it and if nothing has
te ha pasado algo contarlo y si no te ha
happened to you look for something that
pasado nada buscar algo que te haya
could have happened to you to tell it on
podido haber pasado para contarlo en
social networks so that
redes sociales
everyone has support in that
tenga todo el mundo a apoyar en ese
sense i don't agree with the
sentido no estoy de acuerdo lo del
speech of fear of telling it
discurso del miedo a contarlo
currently i'm not happy to be welcomed
actualmente no me alegra ser bienvenidos
at least not on social networks you are
por lo menos no en redes sociales te
completely wrong in this with all due
equivocas completamente en esto con todo
respect it's not easy to tell that your
el respeto no es fácil contar que tu
partner abuses you when your
pareja te maltrata cuando tu entorno
social environment is not the same
social no es el mismo
the majority of abused girls do not
la mayoría de chicas maltratadas no
have  social media and live in a it wouldn't
tienen redes sociales y viven en un no
be good to inform you you know let's be
estaría bien informarte sabes seamos
realistic we're making a
realistas estamos haciendo una
comparison the majority of
comparación la mayoría de chicas
abused girls don't have social media, they
maltratadas no tienen redes sociales ha
said that house has already taken the
dicho esa casa ya se ha llevado el
abuse but we're going like kidnapped
maltrato pero vamos en plan secuestrada
and everything not
y todo no
in two identical situations we're not talking
en dos situaciones idénticas no hablamos
about the number of cases you think it's
de cantidad de casos tú crees que es más
easier for a man to talk about being
fácil para un hombre hablar de que lo
abused than for a woman to talk about being
maltratan que para una mujer hablar de
abused you're telling me that
que la maltratan me estás contando eso
a man can't go out and say that he's being
un hombre no puede salir y decir que le
abused okay you can't say that it's
maltratan vale no puedes decir eso es
like power can what happens is that what
como poder puede lo que pasa que lo que
's in fashion is feminism and you yourself
está de moda es el feminismo y tú mismo
are here
está aquí
saying in the live that
diciendo en el directo que hace falta
feminism is needed and that feminism is needed
feminismo y que hace falta el feminismo
and all that stuff this be you are here
y todo el rollo este sea tú estás aquí
claiming in your live I don't know
reivindicando en tu directo no sé
how many thousands of people that
cuántas miles de personas que hace falta
feminism is needed when the salt no longer
feminismo cuando la sal ya no
a man can talk about abuse of course and
un hombre puede contar maltrato claro y
should take the steps that we are taking for
debe dar los pasos que estamos dando por
what feminism fights for the greatest is
lo que pelea el feminismo el mayor es
precisely because the
precisamente porque se pueda creer el
testimony of a woman can be believed because if
testimonio de una mujer porque si
simply for being a woman she could
simplemente por ser una mujer pudo
report the million for insults of course she
denunciar al millón por insultos claro
could have put it in  a big mess
que pudo lo hubiera metió en un lío
is a snap barbarity Marta what you
es una snap barbaridad marta lo que
're saying is not about informing yourself
estás diciendo no se trata de informarte
it's about being a little coherent currently
es de ser un poco coherente actualmente
yes there are obviously a lot of
sí que existen obviamente un montón de
women who are afraid of being able to say it
mujeres que tienen miedo a poder decirlo
or what could happen if they say it or
oa lo que podría pasar si lo dicen o lo
whatever but I assure you that in the few
que sea pero te aseguro que en los pocos
cases of abused men that there are
casos de hombres maltratados que hay
okay because obviously there is a minority
vale porque obviamente hay una minoría
compared to women,
en comparación a las mujeres de eso
we agree on that but I assure you it is
estamos de acuerdo pero te aseguro es
much more difficult to say it being a
muchísimo más difícil decirlo siendo un
man than being a woman and more so in
hombre que siendo la mujer y más en los
closed groups okay because I'm not
grupos cerrados vale porque ya no estoy
talking about social networks in
hablando de redes sociales en redes
social networks obviously it is much
sociales obviamente es muchísimo más
easier to express your case it is undeniable that
fácil expresar tu caso es innegable que
if you are a girl and you have some problem or
si eres chica y tienes algún problema o
so many have had some type of abuse
tantas tenido algún tipo de maltrato
some type of rape more
algún tipo de violación más jo
welcome or something some type of
bienvenido o algo algún tipo de
discrimination in some sense much
discriminación algún sentido muchísimo
easier if you are a woman to express it but the thing is that
más fácil si eres mujer expresar lo pero
even in the closed circles that
es que incluso en los círculos cerrados
you talk about that don't have one in which it
de los que tú hables que no tienen en el
is much easier for
que sea muchísimo más fácil que el
feminism to fight look at it by Rocío
feminismo lucha mirarlo de rocío
Carrasco I have made a video for tomorrow
carrasco he hecho un vídeo para mañana
it is simply the testimony of a woman
sea simplemente el testimonio una mujer
the feminist, the proof is already screwed
la feminista ya la prueba ya está a
any woman appears more good night
cualquier mujer aparece más buena noche
right or right
de derecha o de derecha
your testimony is not worth that much but
tu testimonio no vale tanto pero ya
tomorrow any woman feels like
mañana cualquier mujer se le apetece
smoking her boyfriend and it was the truth the
fumar al novio y lo fuera la verdad la
lie with her testimony and there is
mentira con su testimonio y ya está
access to those social networks virtue do you
acceso a esas redes sociales virtud te
really believe that a man has it
crees de verdad que un hombre lo tiene
easier if you believe that I can go in
más fácil si tú crees que yo puedo ir en
a group of men and tell them that my
un grupo de hombres y decirles que mi
wife mistreats me tweet is that and they
mujer me maltrata tweet es eso y
literally laugh in your [ __ ] face I
literalmente se ríen en tu [__] cara
mean you're telling me here in a
o sea tú me estás diciendo aquí en un
live broadcast that if you have that problem you can't
directo que si tú tienes ese problema no
go to your friends and tell them that
puedes ir a tus amigos a decirles eso
because they'll laugh at you it
porque se ríen de ti
would be in your [ __ ] face and it would be in your [ __ ]
sería en tu [__] cara y sería en tu [__]
face from the first to the last one to whom you
cara desde el primero al último al que
tell it as is and they don't pay
se lo cuentes tal cual y no te presten
attention to you I mean you probably
mi atención es decir probablemente le
tell him god my wife hit me today they
dices dios que mi mujer me ha pegado hoy
laugh at you immediately and traffic a
se ríen de ti al momento y trafica un
movement that hates him what a fool that
movimiento que lo odia qué tonto que
literally against is the same one in the
literal se contra es el mismo en el
live broadcast they will
directo
remember him for the next three
lo recuerdan durante las próximas tres
weeks the fool who hits the woman
semanas el tonto que le pega a la mujer
of skin is that that is not going to happen
de piel es que eso no va a pasar el
defending an oh how difficult it is for
defender un ay qué difícil es para la
women to speak is a bad argument thanks
mujer hablar es un mal argumento gracias
what do you think  that they do well to suspend the
qué crees que hacen bien suspender las
demonstrations on the 8th of December,
manifestaciones del 8 dm buscando
obviously there should not be demonstrations
obviamente no debe haber manifestaciones
at night,
de noche m
the problem with the committee, no, no, no, we are not in the same position,
el problema del comité no no no nos
obviously they should be done in
formas obviamente deberían hacerse de
another way, well, you
otra forma
can demonstrate on
lance pues te puedes manifestar por
social media, well, do a lot of
redes sociales pues hacer un montón de
different things, no, no, it's not about the
cosas diferentes no no ya no se trata de
8th of December demonstrations anymore, I mean, I think
manifestaciones del 8 pm en plan creo
that any kind
que se deberían cancelar cualquier clase
of demonstration should be canceled, especially in the
de manifestación y más en la forma en la
situation we are in. Don't be a [ __ ],
situación al que estamos no esté [__]
but no, no, it's not because of the 8th of March, I mean,
pero no no no es por el 8 m es decir
any demonstration, I think that
cualquier manifestación creo yo que no
shouldn't be done. Say, if you are
debería hacerse decir si tú eres ahora
a woman right now and you have problems with
mismo una mujer y tienes problemas de
harassment, rape, whatever, like, someone
acoso de violaciones de lo que lo que
said a word to you on
sea en plan que te han dicho una palabra
the street and it offended you, it is
por la calle y te ha ofendido lo tienes
extremely easy for you to tell anyone, whether it be on
extremadamente fácil de contar lo sea
social media, whether it be in
por redes sociales sean círculos
close circles, or to the police, and they will listen to you,
cercanos sea a la policía y te harán
that's how it works in 2021,
caso es cómo funciona 2021
maybe in 2015, in 2014, it was different,
quizá en en 2015 en 2014 fuera diferente
but currently, if you are a woman, it is
pero actualmente si eres mujer lo tienes
very easy for you to
muy fácil
talk about this kind of
a la hora de hablar sobre esta clase de
employment, similar to a million, it is so
empleo similar a un millón lo tiene tan
easy that feminism, for which she fights
fácil que el feminismo por lo que lucha
for the law on gender violence, for
por la ley de violencia de género por
example, does not have it so easy.
ejemplo no lo tiene tan fácil que
simply with the testimony a woman
simplemente con el testimonio una mujer
puts you in the dungeon
te mete en el calabozo
for normal okay do you think that's fine
por lo normal vale te parece eso bien
topic 7 more which I don't see as bad it's not
tema 7 más lo cual no lo veo mal no es
something that I'm criticizing or anything like that
algo que esté criticando ni mucho menos
I'm just like
yo solamente estoy como contra
counterarguing to the girl who was
argumentando a la chica que está
speaking before saying how difficult it
hablando antes diciendo de qué difícil
is for us to talk but that's not
es hablar para nosotras pero eso no es
false we are in the situation in which there has
falso estamos en la situación en la que
never been
en el que nunca jamás había habido
so much ease to explain the
tantísima facilidad para explicar los
problems that you have and the kind of
problemas que tienes y la clase de
harassment and discrimination that you suffer
acosos y discriminaciones que sufrir se
in your day to day lives by
en vuestro día a día por parte de la
women we have never ever been in
mujer nunca jamás habíamos estado en
this situation and I think that we have reached a
esta situación y creo que ha llegado un
point where the
punto en el que es hasta extremo el
support that you have for anything
apoyo que tenéis por cualquier cosa que
you say is extreme okay to the point where it's not
digáis vale hasta el punto en el que no
even possible to contrast the things that you
se llega ni a contrastar las cosas que
say in many cases
decís en muchos casos
[Music]
[Música]
these photos should go you from here you have
estas fotos deben ir usted de aquí tiene
these photos of you here who
estas fotos de ustedes aquí quienes
because according to him when I made the
porque según él cuando yo le hice el
video and his followers I for you
vídeo y sus seguidores yo para ti me por
why
qué
and he called his editor a witch and that
y él llamaba bruja a su editor y que
this was his editor
éste era su editor
according to him the meme was made with
según él el meme se hacía con la cara de
his editor's face and I said no no no no no in your
su editor y yo dije no no no no no en tu
fandom is done with the face of your ex
fandom se hace con con la cara de tu ex
girlfriend
novia
elisa thank you very much anyway he said a
elisa muchas gracias en fin ha dicho un
couple of things with the management I
par de cosillas con la gestión de
agree with him but of course since I
acuerdo con él pero claro al estar yo de
agree with the things he said it
acuerdo con las cosas que ha dicho se
contradicts some other nonsense that he
contradice con otra tontería que ha
said okay I think he really doesn't think he does
dicho vale yo creo que él realmente no
n't think a lot of the things he's
piensa no piensa muchas de las cosas que
said in this live and a class he's
ha dicho en este directos y una clase
saying to look good it's going to
está diciendo para quedar bien va a
look good okay
quedar bien vale
tomorrow we'll see if anything
mañana veremos si acaso la reacción de
Romano's reaction seems like look we're going to be one thing
romano parece mira vamos a ser una cosa
we're going to do one more thing the thing okay I'm
vamos a hacer una cosa más la cosa vale
going to upload this to youtube okay now
esto lo voy a subir a youtube vale ahora
as it goes these people
tal y como vaya la cama de estos
uploading to youtube this narrow like
subiéndose a youtube este estrecho como
everyone else not
todos no
the reaction of rolling at almost an hour
la reacción de rodadura a casi una hora
okay but
vale pero
and all of you who are watching this video
y todos los que estáis viendo este vídeo
go to facebook
os vais a facebook
and click here to share
y le dais aquí a compartir
okay to the last video that I uploaded
vale al último vídeo que he subido
tomorrow we'll
mañana
see the one of rome rome's response
vemos el de roma la respuesta de roma
okay
vale
if there are shared accounts guys
si hay cuentas compartidas chicos
how many do we ask
cuántas pedimos
500 shared would be good almost 500
500 compartidas estarían bien casi 500
shared easy
compartidas fácil
if tomorrow there is when I go live
si mañana hay cuando yo vaya a ser
five hundred shared on this
directo quinientas compartidas en esto
in the last  video that was uploaded
en el último vídeo que subió
tomorrow we'll see Rome's response in
mañana vemos la respuesta de roma en
your hands I'll leave it in our hands
vuestras manos lo dejo en nuestras manos
guys girls sorry don't be
de los chicos chicas perdone no se
offended girls better go in after hands of a
ofendan mejor chicas entre tras manos de
thousand
mil
I'm going to put 500 if tomorrow we go in and
me voy a poner 500 si mañana entramos y
find 1000 it
nos encontramos con 1000
's like always it's worth your fingers
es como los siempre le vale los dedos
your hands
vuestras manos
guys I'm leaving thank you very much for the
chicos me voy muchísimas gracias por el
time but it's too late see you
rato pero ya es muy tarde nos vemos
tomorrow the dog the dog like jumps
mañana el perro el perro como botes